# Donghuo Zeng



**Data personal** Male, unmarried, 12/25/1989(Birth), China.

## **Contact**

090-9768-8959 donghuozeng@gmail.com 7 Chome-7-3-701, Hikarigaoka, Nerima city, Tokyo. Homepage Google Scholar Twitter (@dhjulianzeng)

## **Skills**

Deep learning/Machine learning, Audio-visual cross-modal learning, NLP, Tensorflow/Keras, Python.

# Hobby 🕶

Reading, trip and sports.

# **Summary**

I am a AI researcher of KDDI Research, Inc. Before that, I graduated from NII last September, I received PhD there and worked as full-time researcher since then, till March this year. My main research topics: multimodal information retrieval in Computer Vision and name entity recognition & relation extraction in Natural Language Processing. Recently, I am working on representation learning for multimodal information retrieval and AI dialogue tasks.

## **Education**

### Ph.D degree(Oct. 2017 - Sep. 2020)

University Name: National Institute of Informatics, SOKENDAI

Major: Informatics

School Address: 2-1-2, Hitotsubashi Chiyodaku, Tokyo, Japan. 101-8430

School URL: https://www.nii.ac.jp/en/

Research topics: Multimodal information retrieval, representation learning.

## Master degree (Sep. 2015 - Jul. 2017)

University Name: Harbin Institute of Technology

School Name: School of computer science and engineering

Major: Software Engineering

School Address: NO.92 xidazhi Street, Nangang District, Harbin city, China.

School URL: http://en.hit.edu.cn/

Research topics: Name entity recognition, relation extraction, NLP

#### Bachelor degree (Sep. 2009 - Jul. 2013)

University Name: Tianjin Polytechnic University

School Name: School of computer science and engineering

Major: Software Engineering School URL: http://en.tjpu.edu.cn/

# **Work Experience**

Aug, 2021-Now: KDDI Research, Inc. Al Researcher. Oct, 2020- Mar, 2021: National Institute of Informatics, Researcher.

Oct, 2017- Sep, 2020: National Institute of Informatics, Researcher Assistant.

Nov, 2018: University of Illinois at Urbana-Champaign (USA), Research Visitor.

Sep, 2015- June, 2017: HIT, Researcher Assistant.

Nov, 2020: KDDI Research, Inc., Internship

Sep, 2013- June, 2014: DEPPON LOGISTICS Co Ltd, Data Analyst Assistant.

# **Publication list**

#### **Journal**

Donghuo Zeng, Yi Yu, Keizo Oyama: Deep Triplet Neural Networks with Cluster-CCA for Audio-Visual Cross-Modal Retrieval. ACM Transactions on Multimedia Computing, Communications, and Applications July 2020.16(3): pp.76:1-76:23.

Donghuo Zeng, Chengjie Sun, Lei Lin, Bingquan Liu. LSTM-CRF for Drug-Named Entity Recognition, Entropy 19.6 (2017), pp.283.

### **Conference (regular paper)**

Donghuo Zeng, Yi Yu, Keizo Oyama. MTM Dataset for Joint Representation Learning among Sheet Music, Lyrics, and Musical Audio, The 8th Conference on Sound and Music Technology (CSMT) 2020. (Accepted).

Donghuo Zeng, Yi Yu, Keizo Oyama. Unsupervised Generative Adversarial Alignment Representation for Sheet music, Audio and Lyrics. The Sixth IEEE International Conference on Multimedia Big Data (BigMM) 2020: pp.162-165.

Donghuo Zeng, Yi Yu, Keizo Oyama. Audio-Visual Embedding for Cross-Modal Music Video Retrieval through Supervised Deep CCA, IEEE International Symposium on Multimedia (ISM) 2018, pp.143-150.

#### Short papers/poster:

Donghuo Zeng, Keizo Oyama. Learning Joint Embedding for Cross-Modal Retrieval, ICDM workshop 2019, pp.1070-1071.

Haoting Liang, Donghuo Zeng, Yi Yu, and Keizo Oyama. Personalized Music Recommendation with Triplet Network, Forum on Data Engineering and Information Management (DEIM), 2019.

Yi Yu, Samuel Beuret, Donghuo Zeng, Keizo Oyama. Deep learning of human perception in audio event classification, IEEE International Symposium on Multimedia (ISM) 2018, pp.188-189.

Donghuo Zeng, Chengjie Sun, Lei Lin, Bingquan Liu: Enlarging drug dictionary with semi-supervised learning for Drug Entity Recognition, International Conference on Bioinformatics and Biomedicine (BIBM) 2016: pp.1929-1931.